Altay Aydemir

Birth: January 14, 1994 / Turkey

Location: Berlin, Germany

Visa: EU Blue Card (valid until 2023) Email: altay.aydemir@icloud.com

Summary

I'm a software engineer with 4+ years of experience, mostly focused on the user-facing side of the digital products. I enjoy transforming an idea into something tangible if it's solving a problem I empathize with. I prefer to start small, iterate fast, break stuff, and learn from the mistakes.

Technical Background

Areas: Media Streaming, Cloud Storage, Cryptocurrency, Fintech

Interests: Functional Programming, Domain-Driven Design, Humane Product Design

Languages: JavaScript (+TypeScript), Swift

Runtimes and Platforms: NodeJS, Web, iOS, tvOS, Android, webOS, Tizen, Roku, Chromecast

Frameworks and Libraries: React, React Native, Redux, Express

Miscellaneous: Webpack, Docker, Fastlane, TravisCI, AWS, Apache Kafka

Work Experience

Software Engineer at Klarna (Berlin, Germany) [May 2019 - Present]

Senior Engineer at App Client Core (01.2020 - Present)

Got promoted to Senior Engineer and switched to a distributed team (Stockholm, Berlin, Amsterdam) which is responsible for the integrity, performance, security and the release cycle of the consumer application, which is live in 14 countries with average 1M daily active users.

Restructured the localization architecture of the app to support 10 languages with different dialects.

Working on a package based feature isolation initiative in the monorepo to allow product teams to develop their features in a more safe and standardized way.

Doing code reviews (Stockholm) and interviews (Berlin) for JavaScript hiring pipelines.

Engineer at Consumer Growth and Loyalty - Marketing Touchpoint Infrastructure (06.2019 - 01.2020)

Integrated native SDKs of the 3rd party analytics and marketing platforms to the consumer facing app.

Developed several loyalty related campaign infrastructures by using Kafka, NodeJS and React.

On-boarded new teams to the ecosystem by organising workshops and tutorials.

Altay Aydemir 2

Frontend Engineer at Lightcurve GmbH (Berlin, Germany) [Nov 2018 - May 2019]

Worked on the cross-platform Lisk Mobile app, built with React Native.

Implemented Bitcoin support according to BIP49 standard.

Developed native modules by using Swift.

Software Engineer at Putio (Istanbul, Turkey) [Jan 2017 - ∞]

Worked in a small team consisting of three engineers. Took full responsibility on the client-facing applications of the product.

Maintained and implemented new features to the existing web app.

Designed and built the new landing page.

Built a proof-of-concept iOS app with React Native, then iterated on the v2 with Swift which includes features such as Chromecast and downloading media for offline consumption.

Developed an Apple TV application with Swift, TVML and TVMLJSKit.

Developed a web-based Smart TV application for Samsung Tizen, LG WebOS, AndroidTV and Amazon FireTV platforms.

Developed a Roku application with BrightScript.

Built cross-browser extensions with WebExtensions API.

Automated build and deployment processes by using Fastlane, Jenkins and TravisCI.

Frontend Engineer at Vispera (Istanbul, Turkey) [Sep 2016 - Mar 2017]

Re-designed and structured the front-end layer of the core Rails application.

Built single-page apps for complex data entry and management purposes with React.

Frontend Engineering Intern at Peergust (Istanbul, Turkey) [Mar 2016 - Sep 2016]

Built demo apps and content management panel for testing and marketing purposes of the P2P content delivery network by using React.

Education

BSc. Mechanical Engineering, Istanbul Bilgi University. (2012 - 2016)

Graduated in the 2nd place of the department with 2.90 GPA.

Altay Aydemir 3

Open Source Projects

```
Accept Nano (07.2018)

JavaScript client for Accept NANO payment gateway .

github.com/accept-nano/accept-nano-client

Vortigern (04.2016 - 12.2017)

An opinionated boilerplate for crafting universal web applications with modern technologies.

github.com/barbar/vortigern

Ziya (10.2016 - 12.2016)

A local, in-browser editor.

github.com/hwclass/ziya

Bilgi Shuttle (01.2016 - 03.2016)

Cross platform (web, iOS and Android) application for listing the shuttle routes and times of Istanbul Bilgi University

github.com/aydieneue/bilgi-shuttle-web
```

Presentations and Workshops

React Native + iMessage Bridge (React Open Source Meetup Berlin, March 2019)

Introduction to Git (FrontEndCamp Istanbul, August 2017)

Introduction to NodeJS (FrontEndCamp Istanbul, August 2017)

UI Development in 2017 (Istanbul Bilgi University - Faculty of Engineering October 2017)

Last updated: October 27, 2020